Seungone Kim

My main research goal is to make techniques that ensure language models (LMs) are aligned with human values in order to reduce the substantial risks they might have (also known as the 'Alignment Problem'). Specifically, I am interested in (1) ensuring LMs to truly follow human instructions (e.g., Instruction Tuning, RLHF, Fine-grained Evaluation) [C3, P2, O1, O2], (2) teaching LMs to express their thought process with chain-of-thoughts [C2, P1], and (3) grounding LMs to share commonsense knowledge as humans do [C1].

Education

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Seoul, Korea

March 2023 - Present

Advisor: Minjoon Seo

M.S. in Artificial Intelligence

Yonsei University

Seoul, Korea

B.S. in Computer Science

March 2018 - February 2023

Publications

Preprints....

• [P1] The CoT Collection: Improving Zero-shot and Few-shot Learning of Language Models via Chain-of-Thought Fine-Tuning

Submitted at EMNLP 2023

Seungone Kim*, Sejune Joo*, Doyoung Kim, Joel Jang, Seonghyeon Ye, Jamin Shin, Minjoon Seo [Paper] [Code]

[P2] FLASK: Fine-grained Language Model Evaluation based on Alignment Skill Sets

Planning for Submission at ICLR 2024

Seonghyeon Ye, Doyoung Kim, Sungdong Kim, Hyeonbin Hwang, **Seungone Kim**, Yongrae Jo, James Thorne, Juho Kim, Minjoon Seo

[Paper] [Code]

Peer-Reviewed Conference Papers....

- [C3] Exploring the Benefits of Training Expert Language Models over Instruction Tuning The 40th International Conference on Machine Learning (ICML 2023) Joel Jang, Seungone Kim, Seonghyeon Ye, Doyoung Kim, Lajanugen Logeswaran, Moontae Lee, Kyungjae Lee, Minjoon Seo [Paper] [Code]
- [C2] CoTEVer: Chain of Thought Prompting Annotation Toolkit for Explanation Verification
 The 17th Conference of the European Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics (EACL 2023)

Seungone Kim, Se June Joo, Yul Jang, Hyungjoo Chae, Jinyoung Yeo [Paper] [Code]

[C1] Mind the Gap! Injecting Commonsense Knowledge for Abstractive Dialogue Summarization
 Proceedings of the 29th International Conference on Computational Linguistics (COLING 2022)
 Seungone Kim*, Se June Joo*, Hyungjoo Chae*, Chaehyeong Kim*, Seungwon Hwang, Jinyoung Yeo

Ongoing.....

• [O1] Aligning Mixture of Expert Language Models on Fine-grained Rewards Planning for Submission at ICLR 2024 Seungone Kim*, Jamin Shin*, Yejin Cho*, Joel Jang, Shayne Longpre, Hwaran Lee, James Thorne, Minjoon Seo

o [O2] Teaching Language Models to Browse the Web with Natural Language Feedback Planning for Submission at NAACL 2024 Sejune Joo*, Seungone Kim*, Juyoung Suk, Joel Jang, Seonghyeon Ye, Jamin Shin, Minjoon Seo

Research Experience

NAVER AI Lab Seongnam, Korea

Research Internship at Language Research Team

Jul 2023 - Present

I am leading a research project, focusing on reinforcing language models to be aligned to human values [O1].

Korea Advanced Institute of Science and Technology (KAIST)

Seoul, Korea

Research Internship at Language and Knowledge Laboratory

Jul 2022 - Jan 2023

I participated in a research project building Expert language models, overcoming the weakness of a single Instruction-tuned LM [C3].

Seoul National University

Seoul, Korea

Research Internship at Language and Data Intelligence Laboratory

Sep 2021 - Jun 2022

I have participated in a research project building a multilingual language model for low-resource languages via continual cross-lingual pre-training. Also, I have participated in the initial stage of building a Korean Language Model where I pre-trained a 11B sized decoder-only model with korean text corpus from scratch.

Invited Talks

Commonsense Knowledge Consortium 1st Workshop

Seoul, Korea

Presented paper accepted at COLING 2022[C1]

July 2022

Host: Prof. II Chul Moon(KAIST), Chanyoung Park(KAIST), Jinyoung Yeo(Yonsei), Seungwon Hwang(SNU), Joseph Lim(KAIST), Jonghyeon Choi (Yonsei)

Yonsei University Al Workshop

Seoul. Korea

Presented paper accepted at COLING 2022[C1]

Presented paper accepted at EACL 2023[C2]

October 2022

Host: Prof. Jonghyeon Choi (Yonsei)

Innovation Session Series

Frankfurt, Germany

June 2023

Host: Laux Michael (SAP)

Services

O Conference Reviewer: EACL 2023, EMNLP 2023

Secondary Reviewer: ACL 2023

Mentoring

Juyoung Suk: B.S. Student, KAIST (July 2023 - Present)

Teaching Experience & Extracirricular Experience

Korea Army Augmented to US Army (KATUSA)

Sergeant

United States Army Garrison Humphreys

January 2019 – August 2020

I have worked as a translator and a Senior Katusa for Chief Warrant Officers flying Helicopters across the Peninsula, serving for General Robert B. Abrams, the 25th Commander of U.S. Forces Korea.

Samsung Dream Class

Samsung Welfare

Mentor

March 2022 - February 2023

I have participated in the Dream Class program as a Mentor, managed by Samsung in Korea. I have taught Python programming to middle-school students including object-oriented programming, machine learning with numpy and pytorch, and data visualization with seaborn.